<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>World Hacks</title>
    <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on World Hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-FR</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 12:26:12 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>E1 conference 2015 in Toulon - Problem Solved - Recaps</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2015/e1-conference-2015-in-toulon-problem-solved-recaps</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 12:26:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2015/e1-conference-2015-in-toulon-problem-solved-recaps</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;(Cover photo - credit  &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/loiclemay&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@loiclemay&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I had the pleasure to attend the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.e1-conference.com/&#34;&gt;E1 conference&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;strong&gt;Toulon&lt;/strong&gt;. This one day conference was dedicated to &lt;strong&gt;problem solving&lt;/strong&gt; and the talks were oriented towards the main difficulties web entrepreneurs might have faced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/e1_accueil.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Preparing venues at E1 Conference in Toulon - Credit photo : Thomas Gabelle&#34;/&gt;
E1 staff is preparing badges before the conference and Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/ThomasGabelle&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@ThomasGabelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-broadcast:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Live Broadcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had one track with 11 talks in French about personal experience and feedback from past projects which have faced major problems. The talks were recorded and broadcast live with our partner &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bizeo.net/&#34;&gt;Bizeo.net&lt;/a&gt;. I guess that replays will soon be available (and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to edit this post when it&amp;rsquo;ll be the case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/bizeo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bizeo Live TV in house at E1 Conference - Credit photo : Nicolas Lequeux&#34;/&gt;
Bizeo Live TV in house at E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/NicolasLequeux1&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@NicolasLequeux1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;talks:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d try to write a brief summary for each talk. I got really interested in four of them, but the others were quite entertaining. Overall, the schedule was respected and the host (&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/providenz&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@providenz&lt;/a&gt;) was really good at keeping the perfect pace between questions and the next speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;travail-en-mutation:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Travail en mutation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/e1_talk1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Larlet and Stéphane Langlois E1 Conference - Credit photo : Etalab&#34;/&gt;
David Larlet and Stéphane Langlois  at E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/etalab&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@etalab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Larlet (&lt;a href=&#34;https://larlet.fr/david/&#34;&gt;www&lt;/a&gt;) and Stéphane Langlois (&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/langlois_s&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@langlois_s&lt;/a&gt;) were opening the conference with a keynote called &amp;ldquo;Travail en mutation&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;Changing the way we work&lt;/em&gt;)  : they listed various benefits of remote work and showed  several surprising coworking spaces in France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;les-8-étapes-pour-passer-de-0-à-100-clients:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Les 8 étapes pour passer de 0 à 100 clients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/gourrier.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sébastien Gourrier E1 Conference - Credit photo : Laura Mabille&#34;/&gt;
Sébastien Gourrier at E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/lauramabille&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@lauramabille&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sébastien Gourrier (founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://sg-autorepondeur.com/&#34;&gt;http://sg-autorepondeur.com&lt;/a&gt; a French &lt;strong&gt;Drip email SaaS&lt;/strong&gt;) gave us a list of 8 steps that he followed to reach a thousand recurring customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the talk, he offered us a link to two resources about a more detailed story (&amp;ldquo;20 minutes are far from enough to tell you everything&amp;rdquo; he said). Guess what, these two links are landing pages that will ask for your email in exchange of the PDFs. On my blog, I will probably soon tell you a lot more about &lt;strong&gt;drip marketing&lt;/strong&gt; and some &lt;strong&gt;psychological levers&lt;/strong&gt; you can use to convert readers to become customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;le-standard-comme-input-de-veille-technologique:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Le standard comme input de veille technologique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second talk was held by Virginie Galindo (&lt;a href=&#34;http://poulpita.com/&#34;&gt;www&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/poulpita&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@poulpita&lt;/a&gt;) a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/&#34;&gt;W3C&lt;/a&gt; advisory board member and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gemalto.com&#34;&gt;Gemalto&lt;/a&gt; employee. She advocates for &amp;ldquo;Curation about standards&amp;rdquo; : as she explains, it&amp;rsquo;s better to be aware about the most recent decisions in our field of expertise. People discussing are &amp;ldquo;friendly people&amp;rdquo; she added, so don&amp;rsquo;t mind asking questions to them about the last development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spent some time in the past on the schema.org Standardization mailing list. But discussions are held in a too fast pace for me. As I need to be &lt;strong&gt;doing&lt;/strong&gt; things for my own project, I can&amp;rsquo;t spend that time with people whose job/mission is too establish and maintain standards. I totally respect their jobs and we need them, but my opinion is that it&amp;rsquo;s more a full-time job than a hobbie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virginie was giving credit to this, when, at some point of her talk, gave us a &amp;ldquo;recipe&amp;rdquo; for a first-time standard-curation. It was like 30 hours or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;startup-on-s-est-planté-parce-qu-on-avait-trop-d-argent:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Startup : on s&amp;rsquo;est planté parce qu&amp;rsquo;on avait trop d&amp;rsquo;argent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/jp_vincent.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jean-Pierre Vincent E1 Conference - Credit photo : Elodie Delannoy&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;/&gt;
Jean-Pierre Vincent E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/fidjey&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@fidjey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jean-Pierre Vincent (&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/theystolemynick&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@theystolemynick&lt;/a&gt;) named his talk &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We failed because we had too much cash&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; . That&amp;rsquo;s the kind of title which automatically draw your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, JP described the issues they faced after the first fund raising. Their two investors were not web/software oriented people, they made money in hard tech. The dev team wanted to work more or less according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://theleanstartup.com/principles&#34;&gt;lean methodology&lt;/a&gt; but the two investors were not ready to test the product on market until it was all done and shiny. Because of that, the team lost 2 years in developing top of the edge features, while competitors were winning market shares. When the first public release occurred, no one wanted the product anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We failed because we had too much cash &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-twitter&#34; style=&#34;color:55acee; font-size:1em&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home/?status=We%20failed%20because%20we%20had%20too%20much%20cash - http%3a%2f%2fjice.lavocat.name%2fblog%2f2015%2fe1-conference-2015-in-toulon-problem-solved-recaps via @jice_lavocat&#34;  style=&#34;color:#55acee&#34;&gt;Click to Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was attending a talk from Jean-Pierre for the second time, and he is really a nice speaker. If you have the choice to attend a talk from him, don&amp;rsquo;t think twice, you&amp;rsquo;ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;le-généraliste-orchestrateur-du-succès-de-vos-projets:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Le généraliste : orchestrateur du succès de vos projets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicolas Steinmetz (&lt;a href=&#34;https://nicolas.steinmetz.fr/blog/&#34;&gt;www&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/nsteinmetz&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@nsteinmetz&lt;/a&gt;) had a kinda high level presentation about the benefit of having &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@chrismessina/the-full-stack-employee-ed0db089f0a1&#34;&gt;full stack employees&lt;/a&gt; in your team. Though it&amp;rsquo;s really similar to the headline of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name&#34;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;, I am a big fan of this new concept. I love full stack team or full-stack managers, but why should we have full-stack employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are bootstrapping your startup, a task is a task, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the HR to cover it, you need to do it yourself. That&amp;rsquo;s perfectly legitimate. However, once you get a team to work with you, why would you need people to compete for the same skills, instead of being complementary. If Alice and Bob are both doing fine in marketing or coding, it means that none of them is really the expert and none of them can take THE decision when it&amp;rsquo;s required : they simply are not legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-experience-comment-fidéliser-les-internautes:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;User Experience : comment fidéliser les internautes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User experience and interfaces are topics I appreciate a lot. Teresa Colombi (&lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/colombi_tex&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@colombi_tex&lt;/a&gt;) was there to introduce people to the stakes of UX for todays online businesses. She also introduced the concept of &lt;strong&gt;gamification&lt;/strong&gt; (more about that on that blog on day) and examplified with this famous video of &lt;em&gt;Stockholm, Odenplan&lt;/em&gt; underground piano experiment :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2lXh2n0aPyw&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want people to perform some actions, gamification is a powerful lever. If you&amp;rsquo;re running a web startup, that&amp;rsquo;s something you can often use during user onboarding (though it&amp;rsquo;s not common enough yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want people to perform some actions, gamification is a powerful lever. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-twitter&#34; style=&#34;color:55acee; font-size:1em&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home/?status=If%20you%20want%20people%20to%20perform%20some%20actions%2c%20gamification%20is%20a%20powerful%20lever. - http%3a%2f%2fjice.lavocat.name%2fblog%2f2015%2fe1-conference-2015-in-toulon-problem-solved-recaps via @jice_lavocat&#34;  style=&#34;color:#55acee&#34;&gt;Click to Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;se-lancer-dans-le-web-sans-rien-y-connaître:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Se lancer dans le web sans rien y connaître&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/quaniaux.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hélène Quaniaux E1 Conference - Credit photo : Thomas Gabelle&#34; /&gt;
Hélène Quaniaux E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/ThomasGabelle&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@ThomasGabelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hélène Quaniaux (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetmyjob.fr&#34;&gt;Meet my Job&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/helenequaniaux&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@helenequaniaux&lt;/a&gt;) is not the common web entrepreneur. You often hear about people entering the industry after years in a different job or position. But they usually have a strong appeal for IT. With Hélène, it&amp;rsquo;s not the case. She left a great position in &amp;ldquo;Purchase and Packaging&amp;rdquo; in a French multinational company. She had no previous experience of IT except using her email client, her web browser and her smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had to learn everything from scratch. She became a &lt;strong&gt;full-stack founder&lt;/strong&gt; (once again, refer to my home page). She told us about how she tried to hire a CTO and how she learned coding. About hiring a CTO, I had a very successful experience on ODesk two years ago, and I might post about it on the blog at some point. She discovered the challenges people face on the Web, SEO, advertisement and so on. A great speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;des-projets-qui-marchent-grâce-à-l-agilité:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Des projets qui marchent grâce à l&amp;rsquo;agilité&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thibault Jouannic (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miximum.fr/&#34;&gt;www&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/thibaultj&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@thibaultj&lt;/a&gt;) tried to summarize the &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemanifesto.org/&#34;&gt;Agile Software Development Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;. There was too much high-level concepts for me to follow clearly the talk. I think I am biased by the fact I&amp;rsquo;m coding alone : I&amp;rsquo;m not having the need for such a &amp;ldquo;framework&amp;rdquo;.  Using kanban on Trello is enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-ans-la-tête-dans-le-guidon-d-une-startup:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;5 ans la tête dans le guidon d&amp;rsquo;une startup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/flo_leGoff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Florian Le Goff E1 Conference - Credit photo : Jean-Christophe Lavocat&#34; /&gt;
Florian Le Goff E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/Jice_Lavocat&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@Jice_Lavocat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Florian Le Goff (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.9h37.fr/&#34;&gt;9h37&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/madflo&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@madflo&lt;/a&gt;) gave what was, for me, the most interesting talk of the day. He shared many tips for early/advanced startup founders. After a brief introduction about the startup he recently sold, Florian went through the main the pitfalls he and his cofounder faced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He started by referring to something &lt;strong&gt;business incubators&lt;/strong&gt; which are far more common in France than startups accelerators. When you grow up in France, you are told that &lt;strong&gt;doing long studies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;avoiding failure&lt;/strong&gt; is the best for you. Hence, students usually spend years and years at the University and graduate without any appeal for trial and error (in Life or in Business). After these years, biz incubators are a perfect place for people who fear to fail. These public structures act as a safety belt and founders often feels more secure since they have &amp;ldquo;pseudo mentors&amp;rdquo; in the incubator. I use &amp;ldquo;pseudo mentors&amp;rdquo; because most of the time, these people are employees and never had to take difficult decisions for their own company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling secure for a founder is a good point. But remember about the &amp;ldquo;avoid failure&amp;rdquo; French bias : such situations could be toxic and prevent founders to move forward, to fail and therefore to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feeling secure could be toxic for founders as they can&#39;t fail and learn &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-twitter&#34; style=&#34;color:55acee; font-size:1em&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home/?status=Feeling%20secure%20could%20be%20toxic%20for%20founders%20as%20they%20can%27t%20fail%20and%20learn - http%3a%2f%2fjice.lavocat.name%2fblog%2f2015%2fe1-conference-2015-in-toulon-problem-solved-recaps via @jice_lavocat&#34;  style=&#34;color:#55acee&#34;&gt;Click to Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His second point was about startup events and startup contests. In a word : don&amp;rsquo;t apply ! &amp;hellip; Or apply once, just to see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third he talked about decisions founders might take when they are on a tight budget : hiring interns. One again, don&amp;rsquo;t do it, except if the intern stays for a long period of time (&amp;gt; 4 months) and is a potential hire when he graduates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d have loved to hear Florian talk longer on that topic. I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll have this occasion again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ouvrons-la-science-et-les-données-de-la-recherche:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Ouvrons la science et les données de la Recherche&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/julien_maupetit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Julien Maupetit E1 Conference - Credit photo : Kevin Pardo&#34; /&gt;
Julien Maupetit E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/kevinpardo&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@kevinpardo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien Maupetit (&lt;a href=&#34;http://julien.maupetit.me/&#34;&gt;www&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/julienmaupetit&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@julienmaupetit&lt;/a&gt;) gave an introductory talk about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_science&#34;&gt;Open Science&lt;/a&gt;. This is a really difficult topic and I would like to cover it in a separate post. His presentation was clear and he showed the various conflicts Open Science is raising. He introduced the concept of &amp;ldquo;publish or perish&amp;rdquo; (researchers needs to publish to stay in the academic race).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish Julien talked about the advanced some researchers do for open science, especially in &lt;strong&gt;Hard Science&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://terrytao.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Terry Tao&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s collaborative problems are a neat example of what the Research could be tomorrow : people publishing openly about problems they are working on, and collaborating publicly toward the solution. In France, we invented &lt;a href=&#34;https://coq.inria.fr/&#34;&gt;COQ&lt;/a&gt;, an interactive theorem solver. Why won&amp;rsquo;t scientists keep the same spirit and try to combine collective and artificial intelligence to speedup problem solving. One could imagine public APIs where artificial agent could use the crowd data / hypothesis to perform all range of conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;etalab-presentation:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Etalab : presentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/2015/etalab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Etalab E1 Conference - Credit photo : Vincent Maignier&#34; /&gt;
Etalab E1 Conference - Credit photo : &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.twitter.com/Tribaleo&#39; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@Tribaleo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last talk was given by Daniel Ratier and Emmanuel Raviart from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etalab.gouv.fr/en/&#34;&gt;Etalab&lt;/a&gt;. The two speakers were pretty entertaining and introduced us to the organization that Etalab (French Public agency for open data). It was really reassuring to see that, instead of being a slow machinery, France managed to set up an active department with skilled people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the first time for me to attend &lt;strong&gt;E1 conference&lt;/strong&gt;. I spent a really nice day and met lots of interesting folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not been involved in the organization this year (too many events made it impossible for me) but I hope that next year will be different, and if you read that, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to attend :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-readings:f32c1169d82c3ed1d791ef927b81b3a5&#34;&gt;More readings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://larlet.fr/david/blog/2015/travail-transition/&#34;&gt;https://larlet.fr/david/blog/2015/travail-transition/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook enters the authorship race</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/facebook_enters_authorship_race</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 14:15:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/facebook_enters_authorship_race</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For those who know me, you know that I have been terribly impacted by Google&amp;rsquo;s decision to stop promoting the &lt;strong&gt;authorship tag&lt;/strong&gt;. This feature gave me the opportunity, at that time, to work toward my first startup project called &lt;strong&gt;Elokenz&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s decision took many people by surprise, and I was very sad the day George Muller &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/+JohnMueller/posts/HZf3KDP1Dm8&#34;&gt;announced it on Google+&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://apis.google.com/js/plusone.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- Place this tag where you want the widget to render. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;g-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/+JohnMueller/posts/HZf3KDP1Dm8&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;facebook-new-decision-to-showcase-authors:c607594bb427d1a62000574638646972&#34;&gt;Facebook new decision to showcase authors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press release published on June 18th, Facebook officially announced that the social network will &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.fb.com/2015/06/18/using-author-tags-to-grow-your-audience/&#34;&gt;support a new author tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/images/posts/facebook_authorship/melissa-korn-follow.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tag will add extra information when people share your post on Facebook. You know that exactly what it already does with the thumbnail, the title and summary. You can search about &lt;a href=&#34;http://ogp.me/&#34;&gt;og:tags&lt;/a&gt; if you are not already familiar with that technology. Tons of plugins exist to have them in your source if you use a wide-public CMS ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/tags/open-graph&#34;&gt;wordpress&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;http://extensions.joomla.org/extensions/extension?searchall=open+graph&amp;amp;filter[tags][]=&amp;amp;filter[core_catid]=&amp;amp;filter[includes]=&amp;amp;filter[versions]=&amp;amp;filter[type]=&amp;amp;filter[hasdemo]=&amp;amp;order=&amp;amp;filter[newupdated]=&amp;amp;filter[score]=&amp;amp;filter[favourites]=&amp;amp;dir=DESC&amp;amp;limitstart=0&amp;amp;controller=filter&amp;amp;view=extension&amp;amp;layout=list&amp;amp;Itemid=145&amp;amp;clearorders=0&amp;amp;clearfilters=1&#34;&gt;joomla&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see on the above picture, the new tag will be displayed under your photo summary and people can start following you. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get if they were following your Facebook profile, or if a new feature was present which would be like a RSS feed for authors (any idea?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-it-on-your-site:c607594bb427d1a62000574638646972&#34;&gt;How to use it on your site ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity for bloggers/journalists to showcase their work. So how to turn it on ? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy as with other OG tags. You just need to add a new line to your meta section. Here is a sample example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; style=&#34;background: #ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;line-height: 125%&#34;&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;head&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;prefix=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;og: http://ogp.me/ns# fb: http://ogp.me/ns/fb# article: http://ogp.me/ns/article#&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;property=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;fb:app_id&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;302184056577324&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;property=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;og:type&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;article&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;property=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;og:url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/article_slug&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;property=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;og:title&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;My Super Sample Article&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;property=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;og:image&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;https://s-static.ak.fbcdn.net/images/devsite/attachment_blank.png&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;property=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;article:author&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color: #0000CC&#34;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/jean.christophe.gomez.lavocat&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #007700&#34;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the last line who is using the &lt;em&gt;article:author&lt;/em&gt; property. The associated content could either be a URL to your profile, or your facebook id. In order to test your implementation, you can use Facebook &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.facebook.com/tools/debug/&#34;&gt;Debug Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-the-author-be-a-human-or-a-page:c607594bb427d1a62000574638646972&#34;&gt;Should the author be a Human or a Page ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the announcement, it also seems that one can use the URL of a facebook page :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Journalists who manage a Facebook Profile will need to ensure “follow” is turned on on their profile. Journalists who manage a Facebook Page do not need to take any additional action steps.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my personal opinion about authorship is that human should use it, not organization. There is (at Google) a different tag for that, for a better semantic. So, tagging your article with a Facebook page has less meaning for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-schema-org:c607594bb427d1a62000574638646972&#34;&gt;What about schema.org ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who have used the Google+ authorship attribution in the past will wonder why their old tag is not already working for Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is mainly two reasons :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first : with Google, you had to put a link toward Google+, and now you have to put a link toward your Facebook profile (seems obvious right) .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second : the syntax used by Google was based on the widely adopted &lt;a href=&#34;http://schema.org/&#34;&gt;Schema.org&lt;/a&gt;. Facebook never participated in the development of this syntax. It has its own syntax (Open Graph tags).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-era-for-authors:c607594bb427d1a62000574638646972&#34;&gt;A new era for authors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really really glad that Facebook took this move. I am in favor of a better link between content and their creators, and (even if Facebook graph is still an obscure black box) this announcement comes as real positive news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be the occasion for me to start again on the main feature of &lt;strong&gt;Elokenz&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading my first post in a long long while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-reading:c607594bb427d1a62000574638646972&#34;&gt;Additional reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news is not fresh, so you might find other valuable info elsewhere, especially on Social Media Hat&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mike_allton&#34;&gt;@Mike_Alton&lt;/a&gt; post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thesocialmediahat.com/news/facebook-adds-authorship-bloggers-take-note-06192015&#34;&gt;Facebook Adds Authorship. Bloggers Take Note!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 08:07:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;passionate-for-the-world:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Passionate for the world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am almost 30, and after a PhD in nano-physics, I am starting he adventure of web entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Ghost to HUGO</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/newt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 16:08:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/newt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I started to blog 11 years ago.
The first blog system i used, was Dotclear, I moved to Wordpress few years after because of the large plugin and theme ressources available.
Wordpress is a really good blog platform, but it updates itslef too often for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few months ago, the blog moved to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, a really minimalist blog system, based on nodejs.
A KISS aproach to the blog, I falled in love.
The only issue i had with Ghost was about the hosting dependencies, no hard to manage, but since i don&amp;rsquo;t master nodeJs, i spent too much hours to hack into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered HUGO.
Hugo is a static blog generator, written with a language (GOLANG), i use everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, i moved from GHOST to HUGO hosted on Google App engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ghost-migration-to-hugo:aa4d6886edf521b3bf02ded1f8536edb&#34;&gt;Ghost migration to Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost and Hugo share the same markdown notation for posts content.
The fist thing to do : extract posts from Ghost db (sqlite) to individual .md files and move them to HUGO/content/post/ folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code I used to achieve this is here : &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/vjeantet/d1f6cf824a2344dd6b4e&#34;&gt;GHOST_TO_HUGO.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step, move GHOST/content directory to HUGO/static directory.
This way all references like images keeps working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migration completed !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;theme:aa4d6886edf521b3bf02ded1f8536edb&#34;&gt;Theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default theme on ghost was perfect for my blog, but unavailable on HUGO… So i ported the casper theme from GHOST to HUGO, you can find it here : &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet/hugo-theme-casper&#34;&gt;hugo-theme-casper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;publishing:aa4d6886edf521b3bf02ded1f8536edb&#34;&gt;Publishing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;google-app-engine:aa4d6886edf521b3bf02ded1f8536edb&#34;&gt;Google App Engine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added the GAE configuration file &lt;strong&gt;app.yaml&lt;/strong&gt; into the HUGO/static directory, to see it pushed to the Public directory each time i generate the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ appcfg update public
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Blog is now Proudly published with &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;HUGO&lt;/a&gt;, with a theme from Ghost (Casper) !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installer WordPress sur Webfaction</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2014/03/installer-wordpress-sur-webfaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2014/03/installer-wordpress-sur-webfaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;J&amp;#8217;ai récemment découvert l&amp;#8217;&lt;a title=&#34;Webfaction - Hébergeur web&#34; href=&#34;https://www.webfaction.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hébergeur web Webfaction&lt;/a&gt; chez qui je suis en train de déplacer mes sites petit à petit. Je vais sans doute proposer une suite de tutoriels pour vous expliquer en français comment installer tel ou tel CMS sur la plateforme. Il faut savoir que Webfaction est un hébergeur dont le support technique est le plus rapide que je connaisse, mais qu&amp;#8217;il souffre pour le moment d&amp;#8217;une lacune de taille pour le marché français : &lt;strong&gt;la doc et le support est en anglais&lt;/strong&gt;. Par contre, j&amp;#8217;ai pu discuter avec le dirigeant de la société, et il se pourrait que cela change si la clientèle française dépasse une certaine taille critique. Avis aux intéressés &lt;figure class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/smilies/icon_wink.gif&#34; alt=&#34;;-)&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web In Provence #1</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2014/02/web-in-provence-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2014/02/web-in-provence-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Je reprends la plume délaissée depuis un certain temps pour vous présenter un évènement auquel je viens d&amp;#8217;assister à Marseille. Il s&amp;#8217;agit du &lt;a title=&#34;Web In Provence&#34; href=&#34;http://www.webinprovence.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Web In Provence&lt;/a&gt; , un apéro networking dédié aux acteur du web en &amp;#8230; Provence. L&amp;#8217;idée était d&amp;#8217;associer un apéro avec une conférence sur une tendance montante d&amp;#8217;internet. Pour cette première édition, les organisateurs (&lt;a title=&#34;Florent Hernandez&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Flo__Hernandez&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Florent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title=&#34;Florent Hernandez&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/112373548303714842647/posts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hernandez&lt;/a&gt; et &lt;a title=&#34;Alexandre Durain&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AlexDurain&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alexandre&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title=&#34;Alexandre Durain&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/+AlexandreDurain_So-Buzz/posts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Durain&lt;/a&gt;) avaient choisi comme thème le &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Conception Web et Multi Device&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; . L&amp;#8217;invité de cet conférence était &lt;a title=&#34;Stephane Martin&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stephane_m_&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stéphane&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title=&#34;Stephane Martin&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/102644824468826022899/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin&lt;/a&gt; senior product designer chez &lt;a title=&#34;Stack Overflow&#34; href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow/Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt; (la plateforme de questions/réponses dédiée aux programmeurs créé par &lt;a title=&#34;Jeff Atwood (Coding Horror)&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Atwood&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1413&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2014/02/stackexchange-logo-300x100.png&#34; alt=&#34;Stack Exchange Logo&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment j’ai triché à Samsung Launching People et pourquoi ils ont bien réagi</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/09/comment-jai-triche-a-samsung-launching-people-et-pourquoi-ils-ont-bien-reagi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/09/comment-jai-triche-a-samsung-launching-people-et-pourquoi-ils-ont-bien-reagi/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Toujours en cours actuellement, un concours mis en place par Samsung a récolté une très bonne visibilité sur la blogosphère française : Samsung Launching People. Dans cet article je vous explique comment il était possible de tricher à ce concours et comment Samsung gère la situation d&amp;#8217;une manière intelligente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction:f793405d4b5e84d7e854da03128bd2fb&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dans ma série de posts pour expliquer comment tricher sur le web, j&amp;#8217;aimerais aujourd&amp;#8217;hui vous parler du concours &lt;a title=&#34;Concours Facebokk Samsung&#34; href=&#34;https://apps.facebook.com/launchingpeople-fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Samsung Launching People&lt;/a&gt;. La dernière fois que j&amp;#8217;ai décrypté une technique de triche, c&amp;#8217;était à l&amp;#8217;occasion de &lt;a title=&#34;Triche aux Golden Blog Awards&#34; href=&#34;http://www.graphemeride.com/blog/comment-j-ai-triche-aux-golden-blog-awards&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Golden Blog Awards&lt;/a&gt;. A l&amp;#8217;époque, la technique était très simple puisque les votes se faisaient par un simple clic. Dans le cas de Samsung, le jeu concours a été organisé sur Facebook. Il est en général plus difficile de tricher à ce genre de concours hébergés sur le géant des réseaux sociaux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1384&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/09/launching_people-300x230.png&#34; alt=&#34;Launching People&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Model : A framework for innovation</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/06/business-model-a-framework-for-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/06/business-model-a-framework-for-innovation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  If you never heard about the&lt;strong&gt; 30-days startup challenge&lt;/strong&gt; that I am taking, then I suggest you to read the following &lt;a title=&#34;30 days startup challenge&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/tag/30-days-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;list of articles&lt;/a&gt;. Today we will disclose the business model behind &lt;a title=&#34;WordiZ&#34; href=&#34;http://www.wordiz.it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WordiZ&lt;/a&gt;, the application we are creating. By doing this, I am of course aware of confidential issues, but I have the feeling that &lt;strong&gt;people tend to be lazy and stealing ideas take some energy&lt;/strong&gt;. Since I am also some steps ahead from I will describe here, the concept given is the one I wrote down 2 weeks ago, and it as slightly evolved.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  So let&amp;#8217;s start. If I am not clear and if you don&amp;#8217;t understand the core of the business, just post a comment at the end of the blog post.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugoshortcode-1:bee392ce472234e8975e3927201fc468&#34;&gt;[&lt;figure class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1368&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/logo_square_125.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logo WordiZ&#34; width=&#34;126&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a logo for the 30-days startup chalenge – 30DSTART – Day 7</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/creating-a-logo-for-the-30-days-startup-chalenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/creating-a-logo-for-the-30-days-startup-chalenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you arrive on this post by a direct link or from Google, I suggest you to read the last two posts on the 30days startup challenge : &lt;a title=&#34;30 Days Startup Challenge&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;How to find a name for a startup&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;#8217;s go to the main topic of my article : how to design a logo for the startup. Well, it&amp;#8217;s not going to be a nice tutorial like the ones you can find on &lt;a title=&#34;Smashing Mad - Webdesign&#34; href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Smashing Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. Here I won&amp;#8217;t give you any method, just some tools I used to design my logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-font:a2cac112dde8b199720b50e158f79c27&#34;&gt;The font&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to me, the font of a logo is a really important signal to express what is the &amp;#8220;character&amp;#8221; of the company. To find your ideal font there is one resource you should use : &lt;a title=&#34;Fonts Squirrel&#34; href=&#34;http://www.fontsquirrel.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Font Squirrel&lt;/a&gt; Font. It allows you to preview your text in different font and download them. They have only free fonts that are licensed for commercial work. So far so good right? The nice thing is also they have a nice classification system which allows to find what you need easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1342&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/font_squirrel-300x246.png&#34; alt=&#34;Font Squirrel&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30DSTART – Day 4 – Startup Name</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;#8217;t know about the 30-days Startup Challenge, please have a look at my &lt;a title=&#34;30 Days Startup Challenge&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;explanation here&lt;/a&gt;. The post of today will explain in detail how I selected the &lt;strong&gt;name of the startup&lt;/strong&gt;, and what had been achieved in the last 4 days. We are indeed already reaching day-4 and I have the feeling that many things happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-feedback:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Initial feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have been almost 300 people to read the first article (and I got no comment via the blog). I exchanged many emails since last Monday, and I should say that the overall &lt;strong&gt;feedback&lt;/strong&gt; is really &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;motivating&lt;/strong&gt; for me. Thanks to the first article, 10 more people signed up to the newsletter, which is quite a good number. If you want to receive the last updates, I strongly suggest you to do the same :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;subscribe&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;subscribe-pitch&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;
      Subscribe
    &lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Subscribe to our newsletter to follow the 30-days startup challenge twice a week.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#8217;s go into the important matter : How I discovered the name of my startup. You will learn a marketing technique called &lt;a title=&#34;A/B testing&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A/B testing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-finding-a-name-for-the-startup:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Step 1: Finding a name for the startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;brainstorming-a-name:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Brainstorming a name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first move one should make to find a name is a &lt;strong&gt;brainstorming&lt;/strong&gt;. To do that, I recommend you to read the complete article from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/cezinho&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cezary Pietrzak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on Mashable : &lt;a title=&#34;Finding a startup name&#34; href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2012/10/04/startup-naming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16 Tips for Picking the Perfect Startup Name&lt;/a&gt;. I followed his &lt;strong&gt;methodology&lt;/strong&gt; more or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, what I did was to start by obvious &lt;strong&gt;words describing the idea&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;em&gt;words, text, author, simple, quality, expert, job, pro, freelance&lt;/em&gt;. Then I developed with &lt;strong&gt;figurative concepts&lt;/strong&gt; and synonyms : &lt;em&gt;hire me, blog, time saved, pencil, keyboard, screen, web, upload, letters, sentence, paragraphe, phrase, press, discussions, voice, news, writer, desk, workflow, expression, say, curator&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s a long list, but it&amp;#8217;s just the start. You can&amp;#8217;t really name your startup with one of those. So the last step was to make either a &lt;strong&gt;combination&lt;/strong&gt; of these words, or to make them &lt;strong&gt;sound similar to the concept&lt;/strong&gt;s. Here is a shortlist of the different ideas that I wrote down at this point : &lt;em&gt;wordio, voicedesk, best voice, voiceo, voicity, authority, bestsay, sayit, wordeero, kiwordz, voiceero, best voice, bevoice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shortlisting-the-candidates:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Shortlisting the candidates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, that&amp;#8217;s quite a long list. How was I able to select only three or four candidates out of that? I used my friends/colleagues and social networkers. I created a &lt;strong&gt;google form&lt;/strong&gt; to ask them exactly this : &amp;#8220;Which is the best name in this list to describe the value I want to bring to people, say (promoting copywriters skills and help webmasters/seo agency to hire them)&amp;#8221; ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the question opened overnight. In addition to the result depicted below, I got some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions from people&lt;/strong&gt;. One had been added to the list : &lt;em&gt;scribens&lt;/em&gt; . Hat tip to &lt;a title=&#34;Arromazam Pepe&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/112241543943924051468/posts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pepe Arromazam&lt;/a&gt; for the smart suggestion. Below is the graphical result of these votes :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1276&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/names_tagcloud.png&#34; alt=&#34;Names suggested for the 30 days startup project&#34; width=&#34;625&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 30-days Startup Challenge</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  I have not been writing on my blog for many months now. This was probably to learn more and more from online readings and share experience with friends. As you may know, I am still working on PhD degree (Italy//Spain) in the field of nanotechnologies. However, I recently decided to try a &lt;strong&gt;quick and intensive challenge&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;#8217;s call it the « &lt;strong&gt; 30-days startup challenge&lt;/strong&gt;  ».
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1267&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/agenda.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1267&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/agenda-300x214.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;30-days startup challenge&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevage de Sentimancho</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2012/10/elevage-de-sentimancho/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2012/10/elevage-de-sentimancho/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Je participe actuellement à une épreuve d&amp;#8217;élevage de &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presstor.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Ma passion du Sentimancho&#34;&gt;sentimancho&lt;/a&gt;. J&amp;#8217;aimerais vous faire partager ma passion pour cette sous-branche du référencement et vous en dire un peu plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;qu-8217-est-ce-que-le-sentimancho:b79840b9480efc84e7e76231ab2cf69f&#34;&gt;Qu&amp;#8217;est-ce que le sentimancho&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le sentimancho est le nom tiré d&amp;#8217;une épreuve française de référencement. Le but à atteindre est de &lt;strong&gt;se positionner le mieux possible avec son sentimancho dans le classement&lt;/strong&gt; d&amp;#8217;un moteur de recherche français.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En rajoutant des textes pertinents sur son site web ou en liant des accords avec des amis, le site concours va monter progressivement et se détachera de ses concurrents. La plupart de ceux-ci se caractérisent par l&amp;#8217;emploi de techniques &amp;#8220;bas de gamme&amp;#8221;, basé sur le &lt;strong&gt;spam&lt;/strong&gt; et la pollution de pages web non protégées.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derrière ce business se trouvent des gens avec peu de scrupules qui ne se préoccupent pas d&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zdnet.fr/actualites/le-web-propre-un-nouvel-outil-au-service-de-l-efficacite-energetique-39768664.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Optimiser l&#39;usage du web&#34;&gt;&amp;#8216;optimiser l&amp;#8217;usage du web&lt;/a&gt; ni de participer à une course de plus en plus effrénée aux ressources énergétique (une recherche sur google consomme quelques gramme de CO2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comment-aider-le-vrai-sentimancho:b79840b9480efc84e7e76231ab2cf69f&#34;&gt;Comment aider le vrai Sentimancho&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presstor.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Le vrai Sentimancho c&#39;est Presstor.fr&#34;&gt;vrai sentimancho&lt;/a&gt;, celui élevé à la campagne a toutefois besoin d&amp;#8217;aide pour exister. Sans votre aide, pas de réussite possible. Donc si vous :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;me connaissez et voulez me rendre un petit service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aimez la nature et n&amp;#8217;aimez pas le gaspillage de ressources énergétiques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;n&amp;#8217;aimez pas le spam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voulez faire un petit article sur le référencement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Je vous incite à faire la chose suivante : écrivez un petit article sur votre blog concernant le référencement et/ou le sentimancho et faite un lien vers Presstor.fr. Pour celà, vous n&amp;#8217;avez qu&amp;#8217;à copier directement la ligne suivante :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&amp;#8221;http://www.presstor.fr&amp;#8221; title=&amp;#8221;sentimancho&amp;#8221;&gt;sentimancho&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
    En faisant cela, vous aiderez mon site de manière organique, et le monde du web ne s&amp;#8217;en sentira que mieux.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
      Merci d&amp;#8217;avance,
    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p style=&amp;quot;text-align: justify;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;amp;nbsp; JICE
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to transfer money from USD ($) to EUR (€) accounts</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2011/11/how-to-transfer-money-from-usd-to-eur-e-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2011/11/how-to-transfer-money-from-usd-to-eur-e-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I will soon have to &lt;strong&gt;transfer my money from an USD&lt;/strong&gt; ($) &lt;strong&gt;bank account&lt;/strong&gt; (Wells-Fargo) to France (in EUR €), I had to look around to find the best solution. With the help of one friend, I started discovering some solutions last year ; but none of them were satisfying. I thus looked a little bit more on forums and found two interesting threads. One is unfortunately in French (google translate it if you want) , but hopefully the most interesting one is in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://philadelphieaccueil.superforum.fr/t1271-transfert-d-argent-des-usa-vers-la-france-a-moindre-frais&#34; title=&#34;Transférer $ USD vers € EUR&#34;&gt;http://philadelphieaccueil.superforum.fr/t1271-transfert-d-argent-des-usa-vers-la-france-a-moindre-frais&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; read the 4th message (&lt;a href=&#34;http://translate.google.fr/translate?sl=fr&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;js=n&amp;amp;prev=_t&amp;amp;hl=fr&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;layout=2&amp;amp;eotf=1&amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fphiladelphieaccueil.superforum.fr%2Ft1271-transfert-d-argent-des-usa-vers-la-france-a-moindre-frais&amp;amp;act=url&#34;&gt;English Translation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pomsinadelaide.com/forum/money-finance/19410-did-you-use-www-currencyonline-com.html&#34;&gt;http://www.pomsinadelaide.com/forum/money-finance/19410-did-you-use-www-currencyonline-com.html&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; more interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My quest for bank/currency transfers came through &amp;#8216;bank-to-bank&amp;#8217; transfers, &amp;#8216;Western Union&amp;#8217;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.com&#34; title=&#34;Paypal&#34;&gt;Paypal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xoom.com/sendmoneynow/home&#34;&gt;XOOM&lt;/a&gt;. But the final solution I found was to use a dedicated online transfer company. There exist several of them (part of them listed in the second link above). I also followed the advice of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pomsinadelaide.com/forum/money-finance/19410-did-you-use-www-currencyonline-com.html#post145331&#34;&gt;Mark Xpnist&lt;/a&gt; and asked for a quotation to the following three companies :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hifx.co.uk/&#34;&gt;https://www.hifx.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.satworldwide.co.uk/&#34;&gt;http://www.satworldwide.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.currencyonline.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.currencyonline.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to find time to update this blogpost as soon as I have some replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good ressource for currency conversion : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xe.com&#34; title=&#34;Currencies conversion&#34;&gt;http://www.xe.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;____ EDIT &amp;#8211; March 14th _&lt;em&gt;__&lt;/em&gt;____&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to test &amp;#8216;Currency Online&amp;#8217; (I picked up this one at random). In order to test the service, I first prepared a payment of $100 USD to EUR . Two fees were applied on my payment. The first one comes from Currency Online, the second comes from my bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currency Online will charge a fee on bank transfer that are less than $5000 USD worth. Above that amount, there will be no fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wells Fargo will charge $3 USD for a transfer below $2000 to a non wells fargo  account. Above that amount, the fee increases to $10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for my $100 USD transfer, I finally had to pay $107.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time, I plan to transfer &amp;gt;$5000 &amp;#8230; so I will pay $10.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing microdata schema.org in  Yootheme ZOO</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2011/08/implementing-microdata-schema-org-in-yootheme-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2011/08/implementing-microdata-schema-org-in-yootheme-zoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2011/08/schema-org-logo1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-1211&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2011/08/schema-org-logo1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;figcaption&gt;
	&amp;lt;invalid Value&amp;gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;schema-org-logo&lt;/h4&gt;
    
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YOOtheme Zoo – Integration of Google &#43;1</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2011/07/integration-of-google-1-in-yootheme-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2011/07/integration-of-google-1-in-yootheme-zoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;figure class=&#34;alignleft&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2011/08/zoo.png&#34; alt=&#34;zoo joomla module&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>