<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing on World Hacks</title>
    <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/tags/marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketing on World Hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-FR</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/tags/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>30DSTART – Day 4 – Startup Name</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;#8217;t know about the 30-days Startup Challenge, please have a look at my &lt;a title=&#34;30 Days Startup Challenge&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;explanation here&lt;/a&gt;. The post of today will explain in detail how I selected the &lt;strong&gt;name of the startup&lt;/strong&gt;, and what had been achieved in the last 4 days. We are indeed already reaching day-4 and I have the feeling that many things happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-feedback:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Initial feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have been almost 300 people to read the first article (and I got no comment via the blog). I exchanged many emails since last Monday, and I should say that the overall &lt;strong&gt;feedback&lt;/strong&gt; is really &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;motivating&lt;/strong&gt; for me. Thanks to the first article, 10 more people signed up to the newsletter, which is quite a good number. If you want to receive the last updates, I strongly suggest you to do the same :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;subscribe&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;subscribe-pitch&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;
      Subscribe
    &lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Subscribe to our newsletter to follow the 30-days startup challenge twice a week.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#8217;s go into the important matter : How I discovered the name of my startup. You will learn a marketing technique called &lt;a title=&#34;A/B testing&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A/B testing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-finding-a-name-for-the-startup:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Step 1: Finding a name for the startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;brainstorming-a-name:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Brainstorming a name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first move one should make to find a name is a &lt;strong&gt;brainstorming&lt;/strong&gt;. To do that, I recommend you to read the complete article from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/cezinho&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cezary Pietrzak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on Mashable : &lt;a title=&#34;Finding a startup name&#34; href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2012/10/04/startup-naming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16 Tips for Picking the Perfect Startup Name&lt;/a&gt;. I followed his &lt;strong&gt;methodology&lt;/strong&gt; more or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, what I did was to start by obvious &lt;strong&gt;words describing the idea&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;em&gt;words, text, author, simple, quality, expert, job, pro, freelance&lt;/em&gt;. Then I developed with &lt;strong&gt;figurative concepts&lt;/strong&gt; and synonyms : &lt;em&gt;hire me, blog, time saved, pencil, keyboard, screen, web, upload, letters, sentence, paragraphe, phrase, press, discussions, voice, news, writer, desk, workflow, expression, say, curator&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s a long list, but it&amp;#8217;s just the start. You can&amp;#8217;t really name your startup with one of those. So the last step was to make either a &lt;strong&gt;combination&lt;/strong&gt; of these words, or to make them &lt;strong&gt;sound similar to the concept&lt;/strong&gt;s. Here is a shortlist of the different ideas that I wrote down at this point : &lt;em&gt;wordio, voicedesk, best voice, voiceo, voicity, authority, bestsay, sayit, wordeero, kiwordz, voiceero, best voice, bevoice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shortlisting-the-candidates:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Shortlisting the candidates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, that&amp;#8217;s quite a long list. How was I able to select only three or four candidates out of that? I used my friends/colleagues and social networkers. I created a &lt;strong&gt;google form&lt;/strong&gt; to ask them exactly this : &amp;#8220;Which is the best name in this list to describe the value I want to bring to people, say (promoting copywriters skills and help webmasters/seo agency to hire them)&amp;#8221; ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the question opened overnight. In addition to the result depicted below, I got some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions from people&lt;/strong&gt;. One had been added to the list : &lt;em&gt;scribens&lt;/em&gt; . Hat tip to &lt;a title=&#34;Arromazam Pepe&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/112241543943924051468/posts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pepe Arromazam&lt;/a&gt; for the smart suggestion. Below is the graphical result of these votes :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1276&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/names_tagcloud.png&#34; alt=&#34;Names suggested for the 30 days startup project&#34; width=&#34;625&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>