<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>30 Days Challenge on World Hacks</title>
    <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/tags/30-days-challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 30 Days Challenge on World Hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/tags/30-days-challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Model : A framework for innovation</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/06/business-model-a-framework-for-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/06/business-model-a-framework-for-innovation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  If you never heard about the&lt;strong&gt; 30-days startup challenge&lt;/strong&gt; that I am taking, then I suggest you to read the following &lt;a title=&#34;30 days startup challenge&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/tag/30-days-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;list of articles&lt;/a&gt;. Today we will disclose the business model behind &lt;a title=&#34;WordiZ&#34; href=&#34;http://www.wordiz.it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WordiZ&lt;/a&gt;, the application we are creating. By doing this, I am of course aware of confidential issues, but I have the feeling that &lt;strong&gt;people tend to be lazy and stealing ideas take some energy&lt;/strong&gt;. Since I am also some steps ahead from I will describe here, the concept given is the one I wrote down 2 weeks ago, and it as slightly evolved.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  So let&amp;#8217;s start. If I am not clear and if you don&amp;#8217;t understand the core of the business, just post a comment at the end of the blog post.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugoshortcode-1-1-what-is-wordiz-for:bee392ce472234e8975e3927201fc468&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/logo_square_125.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1368&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/logo_square_125.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logo WordiZ&#34; width=&#34;126&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is WordiZ for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Before entering into the topic, let me try to  briefly explain our application : &lt;em&gt;WordiZ is a job board dedicated to web copywriters journalists and bloggers.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Search Engine Optimization, Content and Social Media Optimization
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Search Engine Optimization (&lt;em&gt;SEO&lt;/em&gt;) has always been promoting &lt;strong&gt;quality content&lt;/strong&gt; and pushing for &lt;strong&gt;quality over quantity&lt;/strong&gt;. This has never really happened, and the history of SEO if full with&lt;strong&gt; Google bombing stories&lt;/strong&gt; where basically a page is sent on the top position of google due to many incoming links. Indeed a webpage is defined by a URL (web address) and search engines can retrieve&lt;strong&gt; how many incoming links&lt;/strong&gt; are pointing toward the URL.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1369&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/content_is_kinb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Content is King&#34; width=&#34;520&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  However, the advent of social networks (twitter, facebook, google+) has changed the landscape. Nowadays in addition to incoming links, search engines can also ask social networks &lt;strong&gt;how many time an article has been shared or liked&lt;/strong&gt;. This contribute to what I call the &lt;strong&gt;social impact&lt;/strong&gt; or&lt;strong&gt; social factor&lt;/strong&gt;. People work on the Social Marketing Optimization (&lt;em&gt;SMO&lt;/em&gt;).  So, to make a long story short, an article with many links is well ranked on Google, but an article with many links AND many likes/shares would rank better.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-1370&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/boostwebtraffic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SEO and SMO&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Of course all this is dynamic, and if your page ranks number one today, it will not stay like this forever. Competitors are in the same race.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Hiring famous bloggers to rank better
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  So assume now that you have your website and would like to get more visitors. You will try to be first on Google. For this, often you will need fresh and new content each week/day on your website. A common strategy for SEO people, is to &lt;strong&gt;add a blog&lt;/strong&gt; to your website, and &lt;strong&gt;post new articles quite often&lt;/strong&gt;. However, writing and posting an article is quite tedious sometimes. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here comes &lt;a title=&#34;WordiZ - Hire copywriters and bloggers&#34; href=&#34;http://www.wordiz.it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WordiZ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&#34;alignleft  wp-image-1371&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/happy_writer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Happy Writer working on WordiZ&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;By hiring professional bloggers and copywriters you get two things. First you get some &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt;, but this is not new (see &lt;a href=&#34;#competitors&#34;&gt;section below&lt;/a&gt;). Second you get the fame of the writer you hire, and to some extent his/her fanbase. Assume you hire John Doe to write about electric cars on your blog. After his article is posted on your blog, he will probably post the link on his social networks, and thus&lt;strong&gt;, bring fans&lt;/strong&gt; to read your webpage. Even if it is not the case, John Doe is an &lt;strong&gt;influential blogger&lt;/strong&gt;, so, no doubt that your page will &lt;strong&gt;receive lots of coverage&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordiZ is the platform which will allow you to do the following :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look for writers specialized in your topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rank them by celebrity/influence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask them to work for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the writer side, a job on WordiZ is &lt;strong&gt;more rewarding&lt;/strong&gt; than being hired to be a ghost writer. Your articles will keep your name on them, you will still keep the property of your writings, and you can &lt;strong&gt;build your influence&lt;/strong&gt; on the topic you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;competitors:bee392ce472234e8975e3927201fc468&#34;&gt;Competitors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  So far, many content providers and selling content for cheap rates. They are basing their strategy on anonymous authors creating content in gross amount. They take some percentage on the transaction and the business is done. This is good when you can promote your content and do some SEO / Social Marketing to help people discovering &amp;#8220;your&amp;#8221; articles. However, this is &lt;strong&gt;not a win-win situation&lt;/strong&gt;. Many professional bloggers/copywriters &lt;strong&gt;cannot survive with the rates&lt;/strong&gt; offered by these platforms. Offshore workers are often found among the mass-writers of such platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
   Our service will be different. Instead of providing cheap anonymous content, we will provide content at the right
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-business-model:bee392ce472234e8975e3927201fc468&#34;&gt;What is a business model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  A &lt;em&gt;business model&lt;/em&gt; is made for people to rapidly understand how your business works and how it will bring you some cash. The main goal of a business should be to&lt;strong&gt; bring value to your customers&lt;/strong&gt;. This should be the central thing you keep in mind when you develop your business model. To know more about this, I strongly suggest you to read &lt;a title=&#34;Guy Kawasaki&#34; href=&#34;http://www.guykawasaki.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guy Kawasaki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s book &amp;#8221; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.fr/gp/product/B000QJLQY4/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1642&amp;creative=19458&amp;creativeASIN=B000QJLQY4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=jicelavo-21&#34;&gt;The Art of the Start&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Several methodologies exist to write a good business model. However, recently, a trend occurred due to the best-seller &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.fr/gp/product/0470876417/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1642&amp;creative=19458&amp;creativeASIN=0470876417&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=jicelavo-21&#34;&gt;Business Model Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figure &gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//http://www.assoc-amazon.fr/e/ir?t=jicelavo-21&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=8&amp;amp;a=0470876417&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&amp;#8220;. Instead of writing a long and boring text, people now write small blurbs on post-its and stick them on the &amp;#8220;Matrix&amp;#8221;. It&amp;#8217;s visual, it&amp;#8217;s simple, and it allows flexibility (for creation and  interpretation).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  To summarize the action of WordiZ, I created this matrix for my readers. You can view several facts I did not discuss above. This matrix is evolving a lot. Whenever I have new ideas, I put them on it (not on the PDF below). The matrix help me to keep a broad overview of the project.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  If you have any questions, do not hesitate to post a comment below.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[sociallocker id=&amp;#8221;1363&amp;#8243;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a title=&#34;Business Model WordiZ&#34; href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/Business-Model-WordiZ.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;figure &gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/Business-Model-WordiZ.png&#34; alt=&#34;Business Model Generation for WordiZ&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a title=&#34;Busines Model WordiZ&#34; href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/06/Business-Model-WordiZ.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click to download the PDF version&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[/sociallocker]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-you-prepare-your-business-model:bee392ce472234e8975e3927201fc468&#34;&gt;How do you prepare your business model?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is your turn. Let us know if you have ever used the Business Model matrix. Do you have any trick to plan things coherently? Drop us a line of comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30DSTART – Day 4 – Startup Name</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/30dstart-day-4-startup-name/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;#8217;t know about the 30-days Startup Challenge, please have a look at my &lt;a title=&#34;30 Days Startup Challenge&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost/oldblog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;explanation here&lt;/a&gt;. The post of today will explain in detail how I selected the &lt;strong&gt;name of the startup&lt;/strong&gt;, and what had been achieved in the last 4 days. We are indeed already reaching day-4 and I have the feeling that many things happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-feedback:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Initial feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have been almost 300 people to read the first article (and I got no comment via the blog). I exchanged many emails since last Monday, and I should say that the overall &lt;strong&gt;feedback&lt;/strong&gt; is really &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;motivating&lt;/strong&gt; for me. Thanks to the first article, 10 more people signed up to the newsletter, which is quite a good number. If you want to receive the last updates, I strongly suggest you to do the same :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;subscribe&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;subscribe-pitch&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;
      Subscribe
    &lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Subscribe to our newsletter to follow the 30-days startup challenge twice a week.
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#8217;s go into the important matter : How I discovered the name of my startup. You will learn a marketing technique called &lt;a title=&#34;A/B testing&#34; href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A/B_testing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A/B testing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-finding-a-name-for-the-startup:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Step 1: Finding a name for the startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;brainstorming-a-name:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Brainstorming a name&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first move one should make to find a name is a &lt;strong&gt;brainstorming&lt;/strong&gt;. To do that, I recommend you to read the complete article from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/cezinho&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cezary Pietrzak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on Mashable : &lt;a title=&#34;Finding a startup name&#34; href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2012/10/04/startup-naming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16 Tips for Picking the Perfect Startup Name&lt;/a&gt;. I followed his &lt;strong&gt;methodology&lt;/strong&gt; more or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, what I did was to start by obvious &lt;strong&gt;words describing the idea&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;em&gt;words, text, author, simple, quality, expert, job, pro, freelance&lt;/em&gt;. Then I developed with &lt;strong&gt;figurative concepts&lt;/strong&gt; and synonyms : &lt;em&gt;hire me, blog, time saved, pencil, keyboard, screen, web, upload, letters, sentence, paragraphe, phrase, press, discussions, voice, news, writer, desk, workflow, expression, say, curator&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s a long list, but it&amp;#8217;s just the start. You can&amp;#8217;t really name your startup with one of those. So the last step was to make either a &lt;strong&gt;combination&lt;/strong&gt; of these words, or to make them &lt;strong&gt;sound similar to the concept&lt;/strong&gt;s. Here is a shortlist of the different ideas that I wrote down at this point : &lt;em&gt;wordio, voicedesk, best voice, voiceo, voicity, authority, bestsay, sayit, wordeero, kiwordz, voiceero, best voice, bevoice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shortlisting-the-candidates:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Shortlisting the candidates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, that&amp;#8217;s quite a long list. How was I able to select only three or four candidates out of that? I used my friends/colleagues and social networkers. I created a &lt;strong&gt;google form&lt;/strong&gt; to ask them exactly this : &amp;#8220;Which is the best name in this list to describe the value I want to bring to people, say (promoting copywriters skills and help webmasters/seo agency to hire them)&amp;#8221; ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the question opened overnight. In addition to the result depicted below, I got some &lt;strong&gt;suggestions from people&lt;/strong&gt;. One had been added to the list : &lt;em&gt;scribens&lt;/em&gt; . Hat tip to &lt;a title=&#34;Arromazam Pepe&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/112241543943924051468/posts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pepe Arromazam&lt;/a&gt; for the smart suggestion. Below is the graphical result of these votes :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/names_tagcloud.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1276&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/names_tagcloud.png&#34; alt=&#34;Names suggested for the 30 days startup project&#34; width=&#34;625&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trick&lt;/strong&gt; : in the google form, add an &amp;#8220;email&amp;#8221; field to collect your initial list of email addresses. These initial people have seen the first step of your business, they might be really &lt;strong&gt;valuable&lt;/strong&gt; latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;picking-the-right-one-8211-a-b-testing:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Picking the right one &amp;#8211; A/B testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of the big names above, I did not like &lt;em&gt;Proauthors&lt;/em&gt; at all, so I removed it from the list I was going to test. I preferred &lt;em&gt;Phraseo&lt;/em&gt; instead, but I guess that in English it sounds worst than in French. I had a last-minute intuition and added &lt;em&gt;WordiZ&lt;/em&gt; to the 3 winners :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ScribenS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordiZ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AuthorShop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voicty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this last step of AB-testing your names very smart. I used the &lt;a title=&#34;Picking a name for a startup&#34; href=&#34;http://www.startupbros.com/how-to-pick-the-perfect-name-for-your-business-or-startup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;idea from Will Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; from StartupBros. The whole point is that the &lt;strong&gt;best choice&lt;/strong&gt; is the one that would do your &lt;strong&gt;clients&lt;/strong&gt;. So why not let &lt;strong&gt;the crowd deciding&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1280 aligncenter&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/Unbounce-logo-plus-header-templates-300x196.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Logo Header Unbounce&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the service &lt;a title=&#34;Unbounce -AB testing&#34; href=&#34;http://unbounce.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;unbounce.com&lt;/a&gt; to create four identical &lt;strong&gt;landing pages&lt;/strong&gt; where only the name/logo were changing. Their UI is pretty simple, and I just had to create &lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/possible_names.zip&#34;&gt;four logos&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a title=&#34;Inkscape&#34; href=&#34;http://inkscape.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt;. Then using Unbounce, I designed a standard and simple landing page for each name. Every time I was changing the logo and that&amp;#8217;s it. Here is an example of the landing page I created (you can click to zoom it) :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/landing_page_unbound_scribens.png&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1281 aligncenter&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/landing_page_unbound_scribens-300x255.png&#34; alt=&#34;Landing Page ScribenS - Made with Unbounce&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service is really nice because you can then follow which page received the &lt;strong&gt;highest conversion rate&lt;/strong&gt;. It also saves the email addresses so that you can use the database afterward. Also, &lt;a title=&#34;Oli Gardner&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/108308137946313926397/posts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oli Gardner&lt;/a&gt; the co-founder and creative director is really nice and can sometime answer your questions if you have some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bring-some-traffic-to-your-landing-page:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;Bring some traffic to your landing page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That part has been the worst experience of these 4 days. According to Will Mitchell, bringing traffic with Facebook was easy &amp;#8230; No it wasn&amp;#8217;t !! First, you have to place some ads on &lt;strong&gt;Facebook ads page&lt;/strong&gt;. Once it&amp;#8217;s done, the ads have to be accepted : for me it took three days ! Really &lt;strong&gt;longer than what I expected&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another negative feeling I had was related to the new kind of ads : the &amp;#8220;newsfeed ads&amp;#8221; that appear in between your friends posts. I personally find it too intrusive, but the problem is not even there. If you buy this kind of ads, then Facebook will make you pay for any click on the advertisement. And, as Facebook requires this kind of ad to be linked to a Facebook Page, I lost almost 50 clicks because their were sent to my Facebook page and not to the actual landing page. So follow my advice, &lt;strong&gt;avoid Facebook ads&lt;/strong&gt; (at least the newsfeed ads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatives remain however. The cheapest is to take part in discussions on social networks like &lt;strong&gt;Google+ Communities, Twitter, LinkedIn Groups&lt;/strong&gt; or some web forums. That&amp;#8217;s the one I chose and the ROI is amazingly higher than Facebook. Otherwise, you can also buy some Google adword ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-the-startup-will-be-called-8230:d6faeee7c9e3f5d4701cd8a8bd2c8fb3&#34;&gt;So the startup will be called &amp;#8230;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen, the final name of my 30-days startup challenge is :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;box aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong style=&#34;font-family: Times New Roman,Times,serif; font-size: 18px; font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;WordiZ&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  I already reserved a domain name to put the website.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id=&#34;newspaper-b&#34; summary=&#34;2007 Major IT Companies&#39; Profit&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th scope=&#34;col&#34;&gt;
      Description
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th scope=&#34;col&#34;&gt;
      Number
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
      &lt;em&gt;The following data were averaged, please do not sue me  &lt;/em&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Time spent
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      3 hours per night = 12 hours
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Money spent
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Facebook ads + Domain names = 40€ ($51)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      People in the mailing list
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      35
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Prospect
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      38
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  What next
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  As my creative skills are really poor,&lt;strong&gt; I am looking for someone to create a logo&lt;/strong&gt; that would correspond to the startup. If you are a designer and want to help me, just leave me a message and let&amp;#8217;s start interacting !
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  I also realized while writing my article that my English has become terrible, so if some native speaker could have the time to&lt;strong&gt; proofread my blogposts&lt;/strong&gt;, that would be very nice &lt;figure class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//http://localhost/oldblog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Having said that, the next steps for me are : &lt;strong&gt;creating a mock-up&lt;/strong&gt; of the application and&lt;strong&gt; decide which web framework&lt;/strong&gt; should be used. I currently have three frameworks in mind, but don&amp;#8217;t know which one to select : &lt;em&gt;Ruby on Rails, Django &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Symfony&lt;/em&gt;. I was quite attracted by Ruby, but I read in different places on the web that the code is difficult to maintain and to exchange. Web people, I need your help on this matter.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  &amp;#8212;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Edit : Finding competitors
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not want to start worrying about competitors at this stage, but this has come quicker than expected. While writing a tweet to Cezary to thanks him for the mashable article, I found him mentionning a potential competitor :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet align-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    congrats to @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/justinbelmont&#34;&gt;justinbelmont&lt;/a&gt; on launching @&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/prose&#34;&gt;prose&lt;/a&gt;, a service that helps brands write great content
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    — Cezary Pietrzak (@cezinho) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cezinho/status/337956437261156355&#34;&gt;May 24, 2013&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  The service that &lt;a title=&#34;Prose&#34; href=&#34;http://www.prosemedia.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prose&lt;/a&gt; is offering is slightly different than what we will offer. However, it&amp;#8217;s good to keep an eye on them, &amp;#8230; friendly &lt;figure class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//http://localhost/oldblog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt; Nice name by the way guys.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 30-days Startup Challenge</title>
      <link>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jice.lavocat.name/blog/2013/05/the-30-days-startup-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  I have not been writing on my blog for many months now. This was probably to learn more and more from online readings and share experience with friends. As you may know, I am still working on PhD degree (Italy//Spain) in the field of nanotechnologies. However, I recently decided to try a &lt;strong&gt;quick and intensive challenge&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;#8217;s call it the « &lt;strong&gt; 30-days startup challenge&lt;/strong&gt;  ».
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1267&#34; style=&#34;width: 310px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/agenda.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1267&#34;&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;http://jice.lavocat.name/blog//images/posts/oldwordpress/uploads/2013/05/agenda-300x214.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;30-days startup challenge&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
    

&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    30-days startup challenge
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-30-days-startup-challenge:458ffc3cb429acf6465e98c920a8cfe7&#34;&gt;The 30-days startup challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  As you guess from the title, I will dedicate 30 days in the &lt;strong&gt;creation of a web startup&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8230; Well, I should say 30 evenings since my days are booked in the lab. I will try to dedicate some time after each milestone reached, to write a summary on my blog. To follow my adventures, you can &lt;strong&gt;register to the mailing list&lt;/strong&gt; below.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  All kind of help will be appreciated from you, so do not hesitate to &lt;strong&gt;comment, criticize, share, and talk about my project&lt;/strong&gt;. At the moment the project has barely started so I don&amp;#8217;t feel a lot of pressure, but later I guess I would be tempted to stop, so your help will be the strongest motivation I could receive.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  I will try to make this experience as much &lt;strong&gt;pedagogical&lt;/strong&gt; as possible. At the end of each blog post you will find a table with a summary of different numbers :&lt;em&gt; time spent, money spent, money received, people involved&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-0-the-idea:458ffc3cb429acf6465e98c920a8cfe7&#34;&gt;Step 0  : The idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  To make a long story short, let&amp;#8217;s summarize the project and day 0 (Monday 20th May).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  First, the project has two main targets  : &lt;strong&gt;content producers&lt;/strong&gt; (journalists, web copyrighter,s bloggers) and &lt;strong&gt;publishers/brand promoters&lt;/strong&gt; (e-magazine, webmasters, SEO agencies, and PR agencies).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  Here is the value proposition for each market segment  :
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;For writers&lt;/span&gt;  : Promoting your writing skills and expertise and providing you with job offers and clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For publishers  : Finding the best writer for your business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  This is the end of the first post. In the next post, I will explain you how I selected the&lt;strong&gt; name of the startup&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  How to follow me
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
  First thing is to &lt;strong&gt; subscribe to the mailing list&lt;/strong&gt; to follow the complete challenge. You can also &lt;strong&gt;follow me on&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a title=&#34;Profile google+&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/113400244614302404694/posts?tab=XX&amp;authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a title=&#34;Twitter - Jean-Christophe Lavocat&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jice_lavocat&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you want. On twitter and Google+, please use the hashtag #30DSTART to mention the challenge. That will make conversation easier to occur.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>